大家好, 我是Dan Reecer
来自Acala的增长副总裁
我已经在Acala团队中好几个月了
而之前花时间在
Web3 基金会上
我曾在那里帮助发起Polkadot以及
Kusama。今天，我可能会
说得很快
希望能够把这视频
维持在5到7分钟内
我要谈论的是
Polkadot和Kusama 的平行链竞拍
以及众贷相关的过程
及如何在其中一个链上启动
一个区块链
你可能知道的 Polkadot 和 Kusama 是
一个多链生态系统
连接在一起
而这一些区块链被称为
平行链
将来我们会有至少
上百个平行链在Polkadot以及
上百个
上百个平行链在Kusama，但到目前为止还没有
任何一个平行链在Polkadot或Kusama。
所以今天我要谈谈如何
实际获得一个平行链插槽
作为图表里的小方块之一
您如何能够成为
第一个
在Kusama的平行链，或者
在Polkadot的平行链
以及众贷(Crowdloan)的进程
还有平行链插槽竞拍。所以
这是时间线。您可以在这里查看
那个众贷会先启动
然后接下来，我们会进入主要
的环节，那就是平行链插槽竞拍
就在白色这里
这将会是多个平行链团队
基本上是相互竞拍的
试图赢得这次的竞拍。
竞拍胜者将会前进
并获取一个插槽
在绿色中。一旦您获取一个插槽
您已经正式开启
Kusama 或 Polkadot 上的平行链
而您的团队可以开始
启动您的应用程序
并在其上面创建应用程序等等。
这最终将会是
Polkadot和Kusama的愿景。
然后您可以在这最后的部分看到
此插槽的实际结束时间
该团队
获取的插槽
然后接下来会发生的一些事情
包括众贷资金的
返回
给贡献者等等
接下来我将会谈到所有这些
幻灯片。
所以我将从平行链插槽竟拍开始
因为您需要了解这个
而接着才进入众贷的课题。所以
一个平行链插槽竟拍本质上是
像我所说过的
以团队竞拍模式来尝试
赢得其中一个插槽
每次竟拍最终都在进行
一个槽, 而且可以分成较小的槽位
但最终
在 Polkadot 上，它最多只可以长达 24 个月
但有些团队可能决定竟选
较短暂的时间，但就以这个简单的情况
只是假定了最长的时段。
那些参与竟拍的团队
有两种选择方法
实际上是
出价和用于出价的资金
所以
首先，如果您有一个账户
比如 Kusama 的话，您有一个
持有 KSM 的钱包，想使用于
此竟拍活动
而您不需要让社区成员来参与
这可以成为一种选择。
在多数的情况下
很可能是
这里的第二个选择，那就是使用
众贷模块
在这种情况下，您实际上是这样的
在Kusama的KSM众贷
或DOT众贷的情况下
来自您的社区成员和您
基本上一起筹集资金，这样您就可以了
可以使用
在平行链插槽竟拍中。
这种情况会发生多长的时间？
平行链插槽竟拍是一次性而
而各别进行的，但它其实是
大约每两周一次，所以
在Polkadot和Kusama生态系统中
这些事情将会以此
基础上继续地进行
所以，众贷首先是
like i said are used
for the opening bid in an auction so
teams will
crowdsource these tokens and then use
them in that parachain auction at the
next step.
If you're a user and you contribute KSM
to a Kusama parachain or if you
contribute DOT to a Polkadot parachain
you're essentially agreeing to locking
those tokens for the duration of that
parachain slot.
In the example that I used earlier
let's assume 24 months
then after 24 months your original
principle is returned back to you so
it's essentially no loss and a much more
ethical model
than we've seen in the past with things
like ICOs because in this case
you really hold the team accountable for
actually delivering on their
vision in their white paper because they
need to add value to their network
because they're actually not raising
any funds directly from you as the
community member.
Last, I kind of hinted at this
just now but
the funds that are contributed in
KSM or in DOT
are never touched by the team so there's
no worries about
teams raising money and running away
with it not delivering on what they
promised. All
the interests are really aligned here
and the team is really held accountable.
In the crowdloan,
this is kind of what it looks like.
You've got multiple teams
crowdsourcing KSM or DOT from their
communities
and that leads into the paratrain slot
auction.
Everything that was raised in that
crowdloan stage is
is not accessible to the team but
they can actually use that
in their parachain slot auction. So you
can think of it like a poker table
at the beginning of the auction all
these teams will basically go all in
with the funds that they raised in
their crowdloan.
Then how do we determine the winner?
When the auction starts we will know the
open time
here in the green, and we will know the
close time in the orange over here
and the most exciting point will be when
we hit this close time
the Kusama or Polkadot relay chain
itself will randomly select a time
that determines the end time, this red
bar here. So in this
example you've got Parachain B bidding,
Parachain C bidding,
Parachain A bidding.... E and F
beat A in terms of number of KSM but the
winner was determined at this red line
so
the highest bidder was Parachain A.
This is called an unpermissioned candle auction
and it incentivizes teams to bid
as high as they can as early as they can
instead of waiting until the end like
you might have seen on ebay
where people try to
snipe at the end and get the highest bid.
This is a full walkthrough of this
whole process. You've got
users over here contributing KSM they
contribute in this example to Karura
500,000 KSM. Then Karua
wins the first slot on Kusama and then
begins its launch process so
all of the KSM that was crowdsourced in
this original
crowdloan period is then locked in the
core
Kusama relay chain and then KAR
is then distributed, the native token of
Karura (KAR) is distributed to the
crowdloan contributors
and then at the same time
Karura is also launching so
the Karura stablecoin, the liquid KSM staking,
as well as
the Karura AMM-DEX, the Karura DEX
all go live on top of Karura
when this happens. At the end of
the parachain slot all of the KSM is
returned to the
supporters. Now the
last question that people sometimes
have is: 'What happens at the end of that
slot?' In this example, let's say
that it was a one-year parachain slot
the KSM is returned to the original
crowdloan supporters and then there's
three options for
any team to kind of maintain their
access to the relay chain.
First is to host another crowdloan and
do another parachain auction,
second is to self fund. Karura and
Acala will both have a decentralized
sovereign wealth fund
and over time that will
continue to build and build
so that we can become sovereign and
self-sustainable and actually
bid with our own treasury our own
sovereign wealth fund
for future slots, and then the third
option
there's probably several wiki articles
and videos that you could watch
about this but, the other option is
to become a parathread, which
just means that you have a little
bit less access..
less frequent access to the relay
chain itself.
So that's it in about eight minutes.
Hopefully you learned something. Let me
know if you have any questions.
Thank you, bye.